(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-15T09:23:59.220607",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
白銀の獅子はかけてかけてかけ続けている
The silver lioness keeps on dashing, dashing, and dashing on
もう不安に振り返ることはないから
Because I won't look back in anxiety anymore
百獣の王は九十九を信じるから王なんだ
The king of beasts is a king because she believes in ninety-nine
we have the pride, and it's our reason of pride
それこそ私の誇り
That is the reason for my pride
孤高は孤独の裏返しで
Solitude is the opposite of loneliness,
ずっと一人なんだろうって思ってた
I used to think I'd always be all alone.
前だけ睨んでただ夢へ駆けて 足跡を見失って
Glaring straight ahead, rushing toward dreams, I lost track of my steps.
変わらない曇天 交わさない交点
An unchanging cloudy sky, paths that never cross,
はぐれ山猫だって笑った
"I'm just a stray wildcat," I laughed.
音のなかった世界 満ちて広げていく
A soundless world filling and expanding,
人たちの声や生の目に 曝されて
Exposed to people's voices and raw gazes,
私は変わりつつある 蕾のlioness
I am slowly changing, a budding lioness.
立ってなお爪を研ぐ 友の前歩くため
Standing and sharpening claws to walk before my friends.
白銀の獅子は 群れて 群れて 群れを抱く
The white lioness gathers, gathers, embraces her pack,
それが私を支えてくれるから
because they are the ones who support me.
純白の孤高を追いかけて寄り添ってくれる者たち
Those who pursue and nestle close to pure white solitude—
we have the pride, and it's our reason of pride,
それこそ私たちの誇り
that is our pride.
計算外ふりして縄張りの
Feigning miscalculation,
線を 直角で無差別に引いてた
drawing lines of my territory squarely and indiscriminately.
目指したものだけ 輝くものだけ そしてただ迷うだけ
Only aiming for what shines, what sparkles, and just wandering—
見失う軌道 不安さのモード 導いてほしいと気づいたある日
Losing my orbit and mode of anxiety, realizing one day I wanted guidance.
届かなかった谺 やがて広がりゆく
Echoes that wouldn't reach, soon spreading out,
私たちのねぇ 少しずつお互いを得ていくから
bit by bit, we find and gain each other.
もし遠くずっと遠く離れていても
Even if we are far, far apart,
ルビサックに向け吠える共に声届けするため
howling toward the Ruby Sacks to send our voices together.
一匹の獅子は 最低 最低 先吠えたいのさ
A solitary lioness, at the very least, wants to howl first,
燃えず 時を見守る人のために
burning not, for the sake of those watching over time.
百獣の王は 一緒に 一緒に 先吠えたいのさ
The king of beasts wants to howl ahead together, together.
we care with the king of beasts we got
白銀の獅子は
The white lioness
かけて かけて かけ続けてるもう二度と振り返ることはないから
dashes, dashes, keeps dashing, never looking back again!
百獣の王は 九九を信じるからおとなのさ
The king of beasts believes in the 99, you know.
今なら前だけを この夢だけを 見て走っていられる
Now, I can keep running looking only forward, only at this dream.
後ろの大切な 私たちの群れをまとうだから
Embracing our precious pack behind us,
we have the pride, and it's our reason of pride, それこそ私たちの誇り
We have the pride, and it's our reason of pride, that is our pride.
はい、ということで皆さん改めてまして、ララ、4ホロライブ5期生、獅白ぼたんです！イエーイ！
Hi everyone, once again, as Hololive 5th Generation, I'm Shishiro Botan! Yay!
言うことで、今日はですね、ちょっとまあ、遅れてしまったんですが、周年記念、まあ3周年
So, today, well, I'm a bit late, but for my anniversary, well, my 3rd anniversary...
3周年め終わりまして、4周年目に突入するのかな
Now that our third anniversary is over, we're heading into our fourth year, right?
ということで記念ライブを行わせていただこうかなと思います。
So, I thought I'd hold a commemorative live concert.
今回のね、ちょっとコンセプトがあって、
This time, there's a concept:
ホロメンに歌ってもらいたい歌とか一緒に歌いたいなと思った歌を
songs I'd love to have Hololive members sing, or songs I'd want to sing together...
ゲストさんいっぱい呼んで ちょっとね、披露していきたいなと思いますので、
inviting lots of guests to showcase them, so...
ちょっと最後までたっぷりいっぱいあるんで曲、よかったら見ていってください。
there are plenty of songs all the way to the end, so I hope you'll check them out.
ということでもう早速いっぱいあるんで行きましょう。しょびー！
With that said, there are plenty right away, let's go! Shoby!
もっと早く… “君の場所”へ…
Hurry up, hurry up, to your place, hurry up
祈る声が木霊し続ける
It’s a voice in my mind, makes me run so fast
痛み堪え進む意思を 探す現実(いま)
What am I chasing for? How can I overcome?
加速してく
All I got to do is accelerate for you
we are tossed by the waves of pain and tears
i'm tossed into the fray
I’m tossed into the fray
tossed by various fortune
wake up your brain !
Wake up your brain!
flashed in the sky
it's a burst of sensation
It’s a burst of sensation
“諦め”がくれた安楽 沈滞の世界
Forgot to stand up long ago
いつからだったんだろう? 我の声も忘れてた
Didn’t know just how to try again
膝をつく僕に 君が差し出す景色
So when I was down on my knees
モノクロの朝が ふいに輝き始めた
The view that was monochrome
変わらずにいてと願うこと
Now that I wish, you are just the way you are
変わりゆく時に生きる僕ら
Now that I wish, you never stop going through the world
本当の声線を… 言い得ぬ夢を…
Let your voice be so free, baby, send it for me
君と繋がった空へ 響かせて!
Woah, anytime we are connected through the blue sky
もっと強く… この両手で
Moving up, moving up, to the place, moving up
涙全部振り払えたら
Your heart, my heart, now that they start moving up
“今度こそは…” つぶやく今と
To the touch, to the feel, wanna know everything
傷さえも無駄にしない いつか 君が示す 場所へ
With the spiritual sense of my world
薄い羽が焼かれようとも
Hurry up, hurry up, to the place, hurry up
脳の奥で口を開く
It’s a voice in my mind, makes me run so fast
“真実”へ 加速してく
What am I chasing for? How can I overcome?
we are tossed by the waves of pain and tears
i'm tossed into the fray
I’m tossed into the fray
tossed by various fortune
wake up your brain !
Wake up your brain!
flashed in the sky
it's a burst of sensation
It’s a burst of sensation
何を見ているの? 虚空 見据える瞳
Staring at the darkness, tell me what are you looking for
凛とした肩がわずか震えた気がした
Struggle inside of yourself, it’s now that I can feel you more and more
ちっぽで消えそうだけど
It’s no one but you that I have in my heart
守りたいモノ確かなんだ
It’s no one but you that I can share the whole of my life
虚像の街と 不安定な日常の中
In a virtual paradise, it’s an unstable life
信じられる物は ただ一つ!
Oh, only we have to do is believe each other
もっと深く 感じさせて
Moving up, moving up, to the place, moving up
動き出した心と心
Your heart, my heart, now that they start moving up
自分の目で… そして、触れて
To the touch, to the feel, wanna know everything
感覚を手に入れたい
With the spiritual sense of my world
何を求め 何を許し
Hurry up, hurry up, to the place, hurry up
いくつ抱え 進めば良いのか?
It’s a voice in my mind, makes me run so fast
目覚めがけの可能性を
What am I chasing for? How can I overcome?
たぐり寄せ 加速してく
All I got to do is accelerate for you
僕のために泣いてくれた
You would cry for me, I will smile for you
その瞳を 笑わせたくて
For your eyes that I adore, wanna make them shine more
もっと近く… もっと深く…
Heartbeat with the heat, now it goes so deep
熱を帯び 進化してく
The unfinished dream will come true
もっと強く… この両手で
Moving up, moving up, to the place, moving up
涙全部振り払えたら
Your heart, my heart, now that they start moving up
“今度こそは…” つぶやく今と
To the touch, to the feel, wanna know everything
傷さえも無駄にしない
With the spiritual sense of my world
もっと早く… 君のもとへ
Hurry up, hurry up, to the place, hurry up
たとえ羽が千切れようとも
It’s a voice in my mind, makes me run so fast
歪む 世界 走り抜けて
What am I chasing for? How can I overcome?
感覚の その向こうへ
All I got to do is accelerate for you
“真実”と 加速してく
僕のために泣いてくれた
We are tossed by the waves of pain and tears
その瞳を 笑わせたくて
I’m tossed into the fray, tossed by various fortune
もっと近く… もっと深く…
Wake up your brain, flashed in the sky
熱を帯び 進化してく
It’s a burst of sensation
もっと強く… この両手で
Moving up, moving up, to the place, moving up
涙全部振り払えたら
Your heart, my heart, now that they start moving up
“今度こそは…” つぶやく今と
To the touch, to the feel, wanna know everything
傷さえも無駄にしない
With the spiritual sense of my world
もっと早く… 君のもとへ
Hurry up, hurry up, to the place, hurry up
たとえ羽が千切れようとも
It’s a voice in my mind, makes me run so fast
歪む 世界 走り抜けて
What am I chasing for? How can I overcome?
感覚の その向こうへ
All I got to do is accelerate for you
“真実”と 加速してく
We are tossed by the waves of pain and tears
we are tossed by the waves of pain and tears
i'm tossed into the fray
I’m tossed into the fray
tossed by various fortune
wake up your brain !
Wake up your brain!
flashed in the sky
it's a burst of sensation
It’s a burst of sensation
we are tossed by the waves of pain and tears
i'm tossed into the fray
I’m tossed into the fray
tossed by various fortune
wake up your brain !
Wake up your brain!
ねえ お願い この手を牽き寄せ
Hey, please take my hand and pull me close,
幸せの向こう側まで連れてってよ
take me to the other side of happiness.
このまま人波に溺れそうだから
I feel like I'm about to drown in the crowd,
硝子窓に映るあなたとわたし
with you and me reflected in the glass window.
あの日擦り切れたその時
Back when it frayed and wore out,
世界と綻んでしまったみたいだ
it seemed like the world and I unraveled.
巡る景色が悲しく笑うな
The revolving scenery laughs sadly,
恐れずまぶたを閉じてごらん
so try closing your eyes without fear.
錆びないさ こちらへどうぞ 鼓動の鳴る方へさ
Fearless, come this way, toward the beating of our hearts.
踵打ち鳴らせ どうぞ 心の踊る方へさ
Stamp your heels, please, toward where your heart dances.
新軌道に飛び乗って 逆しまの世界踊り尽くして
Jump onto a new orbit and dance through the upside-down world.
ねえ お願い 止まない愛を知りたいと願うおまじない
Hey, please, the spell wishing to know unending love—
時を越えて朝から夜まで
across time, from morning until night.
ねえ お願い 君を知りたい 何ひとつ重ならぬように
Hey, please, I want to know you, so nothing ever overlaps.
時は誰も待ってくれないの
Time won't wait for anyone.
万国な運命だ 抗えぬ宿命だ
It's a universal destiny, an inescapable fate.
考える間もなく 押し寄せるなら鳴らして
If it rushes in without a moment to think, make it ring out.
迷い見えなくてだって 君を信じてみたいの
Even without seeing the hesitation, I want to try believing in you.
恐れずに一歩踏み出したら
If you take a step forward without fear,
錆びないさ こちらへどうぞ 鼓動の鳴る方へさ
Fearless, come this way, toward the beating of our hearts.
踵打ち鳴らせ どうぞ 心の踊る方へさ
Stamp your heels, please, toward where your heart dances.
錆びないさ こちらへどうぞ 鼓動の鳴る方へさ
Fearless, come this way, toward the beating of our hearts.
踵打ち鳴らせ どうぞ 心の踊る方へさ
Stamp your heels, please, toward where your heart dances.
空飛ぶ列車に飛び乗って 逆しまの世界踊り尽くせ
Jump onto a flying train and dance your heart out in the upside-down world.
ねえ お願い 誰も知らない名もない今をかけてゆくの
Hey, please, running toward an unknown, nameless present,
あの見果てぬ手を目を伸ばして
reaching out our hands to that unseen horizon.
ねえ お願い 君を知りたい 声にならない臆病な朝を
Hey, please, I want to know you, through a timid, voiceless morning,
たとえ何度迎えようとも
no matter how many times we face it.
夢ならば覚めないで 現実なんてさ魅力もないから
If it's a dream, don't wake up, because reality holds no charm.
時は誰も待ってくれないの
Time won't wait for anyone.
蒼き光をともす それは破壊、眠り、ソセイ... ゲシュペンスター・イェーガー
Lighting the blue light—that is destruction, sleep, resurrection... Gespenst Jäger.
傷つきさまよい踏み出した 確かな忍び逢い... ゲシュペンスター・イェーガー
A sure, stealthy rendezvous stepping out through injuries and wandering... Gespenst Jäger.
ああ その背中は
Ah, that back
羽根をもぎ取られた跡がある
bears the traces of having its wings torn off.
小さな何かを信じて もう一度掴もう!
Believing in something small, let's grasp it once more!
赤く激しく鼓動の鋼、痛み、そして揺れる... ゲシュペンスター・イェーガー
Red and intense, the steel of a heartbeat, pain, and trembling... Gespenst Jäger.
どんな外皮をも切り裂き 立ち割るため立ち上がれ!... ゲシュペンスター・イェーガー
Rise up to slash through any outer skin and split it apart!... Gespenst Jäger.
誇りを持ち刃振り上げ 私よあなたよその手よ
With pride, raise your blade—me, you, that hand,
この手は安らぎを知っている!
this hand knows peace!
non それでいい
Non, that's fine.
non 希望涙
Non, hope and tears.
せめて君の微笑み守るよ...
At the very least, I will protect your smile...
青い惑星に生まれて
Born on a blue planet,
違う道を歩いて
walking different paths,
たどり着いたこの街
we arrived at this city
光る粒が弾けた
where glowing particles burst forth.
巡る夜にキミと出会い
Meeting you in the revolving night,
いつの間にか手をつないで
before I knew it, we were holding hands.
笑い声と弾む足で
With laughter and a bouncing step,
どこまでも走れるミッドナイト
we can run anywhere through the midnight.
見上げた空星の光
Starlight in the sky I looked up at,
街のネオンが混ざり合って
blending with the city's neon lights.
憂鬱な日々を忘れて
Forgetting these gloomy days,
痛い・辛いとか、苦い・暗いはもう全部捨て去って
throwing away all the pain and bitterness!
ボクらもっと自由なはず
We should be much freer.
閉ざした羽を開いたなら
If we open our closed wings,
退屈な日々にさよなら
say goodbye to boring days,
夜の街を行こう
and let's go into the night city!
ビルを抜けて 街を追い越して
Passing through buildings and overtaking the town,
さらば青い惑星
farewell to the blue planet!
なんて惚けてどこまで行こう
How dazed, how far shall we go?
変わらないものなど何もないから
Since nothing ever stays the same,
たった一つ 確かな今を刻んで
carve out just one certain present moment.
踊る夜にキミを連れて
Bringing you along into the dancing night,
邪魔なものは何もなくて
with nothing in our way,
歌う声と軽い足で
with a singing voice and light steps,
いつまでも走れるミッドナイト
we can run forever through the midnight.
見上げた空月の光
Moonlight in the sky I looked up at,
街の幻想が惹かれあって
blending with the city's illusions.
憂鬱な日々を忘れて
Forgetting these gloomy days,
痛い・辛いとか、苦い・暗いはもう全部捨て去って
throwing away all the pain and darkness!
見上げた空星の光
Starlight in the sky I looked up at,
街のネオンが混ざり合って
blending with the city's neon lights.
退屈な日々にさよなら
Say goodbye to boring days,
守るよ
I will protect you.
ボクらもっと自由なはず
We should be much freer.
閉ざした羽を開いたなら
If we open our closed wings,
退屈な日々にさよなら
say goodbye to boring days,
夜の街を行こう
and let's go into the night city!
せめて君の方へ 微笑みに希望なのだから
At least toward you, into your smile, because it's hope.
守るよ それでいいの
I'll protect you, that's fine.
せめて君の方へ 微笑みに希望なのだから
At least toward you, into your smile, because it's hope.
守るよ それでいいの
I'll protect you, that's fine.
この声が聞こえるなら 渡り鳥よ導いて
If this voice can be heard, migratory birds, guide me.
命が覚えている 遥かなるあの場所へ
To that distant place where life awakens.
海鳴り 心が怯えに捕らえぬように
Sound of the sea, so my heart isn't caught by fear.
歌って あなたの生まれた国の言葉で
Sing in the language of the country where you were born.
あの場所へ...
To that place...
海鳴り 心が
Sound of the sea, my heart
恐れにとらわれぬように
so that it is not caught by fear.
歌って あなたの生まれた国の言葉で
Sing in the language of the country where you were born.
巡り合えれば 見つめ合えば 巡り合えれ
If we meet again, if we gaze at each other...
瞳の中 同じ希望の光を灯している
Lighting the same fire of hope in our eyes.
まだ見ぬかの地野の花は
The flowers of that unseen land
まるで鈴の音の響き
are just like the chiming of small bells.
西へと向かう風に 憧れよ はばたいて
To the wind heading west, yearning, spread your wings.
はばたいて
Spread your wings.
君の大好きなこの旋律(Melodie)...
This melody that you dearly loved...
大空へと響け口琴(Harmonica)...
A harmonica resounding throughout the skies...
天使が抱いた窓枠の画布(Toile)...
The canvas on your windowsill...
ねえ... その風景画(Paysage)... 美しいかしら?
Hey... Is that landscape painting... beautiful?
其れは(C'est)―― 風が運んだ...
That is— Carried by the wind...
淡い花弁... 春の追想...
The light petals... The remembrance of spring...
綺麗な音... 謳う少女(Monica)... 鳥の囀り... 針は進んだ →
What a beautiful sound... The singing girl... The chirping of the birds... The clock's hand moves →
其れは(C'est)―― 蒼が繋いで...
That is— Connecting azure...
流れる雲... 夏の追想...
The flowing clouds... The remembrance of summer...
綺麗な音... 詠う少女(Monica)... 蜩の時雨... 針は進んだ →
What a beautiful sound... The singing girl... The shower of cicadas... The clock's hand moves →
綺麗だと... 君が言った景色...
The scenery you said was...
きっと忘れない...
beautiful... I won't forget...
『美しいもの』... 集める為に... 生命はやって来る......
In order to gather... 『Beautiful things』... Life comes to be—
君が抱きしめた短い季節(Saison)... 痛みの雨に打たれながら...
The short season you embraced... All while being pelted by the rain of pain...
「心配ないよ」... 笑って言った... 君の様相(Visage)忘れないよ......
“Don't worry”... You said while smiling... I'll never forget that visage of yours...
其れは(C'est)―― 夜の窓辺に...
That is— Smiling down at the windowsill...
微笑む月... 秋の追想...
The moon at night... The remembrance of autumn...
綺麗な音... 詠う少女(Monica)... 虫の羽音... 針は進んだ →
What a beautiful sound... The singing girl... The buzzing of the bugs... The clock's hand moves →
其れは(C'est)―― 大地を包み...
That is— Covering the ground...
微睡む雪... 冬の追想...
The napping snow... The remembrance of winter...
綺麗な音... 詩う少女(Monica)... 時の木枯し... 針は進んだ →
What a beautiful sound... The singing girl... The cold wind of time... The clock's hand moves →
綺麗だね... 君が生きた景色...
How beautiful... The scenery you've lived through...
ずっと忘れない... 『美しいもの』... 集める為に... 生命は過ぎて行く......
I will never forget... In order to gather 『Beautiful things』... Life passes away—
君が駆け抜けた眩しい季節(Saison)... 病の焚に灼かれながら...
The dazzling season you ran through... All while being burnt by the flames of sickness...
「嗚呼... 綺麗だね」... 笑って逝った... 君の面影(Image)忘れないよ......
“Ah... How beautiful”... You died while smiling... I'll never forget that image of yours...
君が生まれた朝... 泣き虫だった私は... 小さくても姉となった――
The morning of your birth... I was still a crybaby... Though I was small, I became a big sister—
嬉しくて... 少し照れ臭くて... とても誇らしかった......
I was so happy... And slightly embarrassed... But so very proud...
苦しみに揺蕩う生存の荒野を
The fields of life filled with suffering
『美しいもの』探すように駆け抜けた
We roam them in search of 『beautiful things』
果てしなき地平へ 旅立つ君の 寝顔何より美しいと思ったよ......
The sleeping face of yours when you set off towards the boundless horizon / I thought that was more beautiful than anything else...
君の大好きなこの旋律(Melodie)...
This melody that you dearly loved...
大空へと響け口琴(Harmonica)...
A harmonica resounding throughout the skies...
天使が抱いた窓枠の画布(Toile)...
The canvas on your windowsill...
ねえ... その風景画(Paysage)... 美しいかしら?
Hey... Is that landscape painting... beautiful?
「私は世界で一番美しい光をみた その数を胸に抱いて Laurent の分も歌い続けよう...」
“I saw the most beautiful light in this world. I'll hold that flower to my chest, and sing for Laurent as well...”
この世界は非現実 ただ刷り込まれたビジョン
This world is unreal, just an implanted vision.
無限遠点 価値観を今 上書きする 変哲のない宇宙
Overwriting the infinite focal point and values now — a featureless universe.
傲慢な神は 目に映らない 光速度で 支配続けるならば
If an arrogant god rules at the speed of light, invisible to the eye,
僕は 僕だけは 奇跡的で 致命的な 少数派で結構
I—only I—will be a miraculous, fatal minority.
I can fly high
あの瞬間、あの場面が キミにとって特別なら
That moment, that scene, if it was special to you,
過去は離れて 行くものなんかじゃなくて
The past isn't just something that drifts away,
傷付く事の痛みより 大事なシーン その全ての ヒカリが今ゼロを生む
Rather than the pain of getting hurt, every important scene—its light now creates zero.
この命という夢幻 まだ錯覚とも知らず
This illusion called life, still unaware it might be an illusion,
二律背反 パラドックスさえ 限界のない 世界線で欺き
Deceiving even antinomies and paradoxes on a boundless worldline,
感情の支配 軌道秩序は 常識さえ すり替えて行くならば
If emotional rule and orbital order are replacing even common sense,
僕の 僕だけの 苦しみさえ 欠損さえ 維持する運命の法則
Even my own suffering, even my flaws—the laws of fate maintain them.
I can fly high
愛のしるし、愛の言葉、明確なるこの記憶を
Signs of love, words of love, this crystal-clear memory
二度と彼方に 置き去りにはしないから
I will never leave behind in the distance again.
いつでもまだキミのそばに 隣り合わせ その量子が もつれ合えばゼロになる
Always still by your side, side by side, when those quanta become entangled, they become zero.
まだ知らない 新しい空 世界線へ繋ぐのさ
Connecting to a new sky, a worldline we don't yet know.
I can fly high
あの瞬間、あの場面が キミにとって特別なら
That moment, that scene, if it was special to you,
過去は離れて 行くものなんかじゃなくて
The past isn't just something that drifts away,
傷付く事の痛みより 大事なシーン その全ての ヒカリが今ゼロを生む
Rather than the pain of getting hurt, every important scene—its light now creates zero.
一番輝く星が一度まわったら
When the brightest star spins around once,
指を一本折った
I folded down one finger.
前に見えるのは小さく握った
What I see before me are just
ただ二つの拳だけ
two small clenched fists.
振り返る想いはただ一つ
The feelings I look back on are just one.
0の時をすぎて数えてみよう
Let's count past the zero point,
あの頃の終わりで奏でる歌
a song played at the end of those days.
この手で開かれる新たな始まりだった
It was a new beginning opened by these hands.
運命と時間、相容れない
Fate and time cannot reconcile;
絶体絶命、明日の息
desperate times, tomorrow's breath.
I can fly!
愛のしるし
The mark of love,
愛の言葉
words of love,
明確なるこの記憶を
make these memories crystal clear.
二度と彼方に置き去りにはしないから
I will never leave them behind in the distant past,
いつでもすぐ君のそばに寄り添わせ
so I will always stay close by your side,
その両手がもうつめ合えばひとつになる
and if both our hands touch, we become one.
Wandering through
ゆらゆらと散る花びらだけ
Only the fluttering, scattering petals
そこに残したままで
were left lingering there,
香りを求めている
searching for their fragrance.
本心はまだあると信じてきたのに
Though I believed my true feelings were still there,
救いという詩を描いて
I drew a poem called salvation,
糸を紡ぐように作ってきた
spinning it like thread.
我らの絆はここで笑っている
Our bond is smiling right here.
今まで愛した過去という歌はこの一瞬を超えて未来になれるだろう
Can the song of the past we've loved transcend this moment into the future?
運命と時間 相容れない
Fate and time cannot reconcile,
絶体絶命 明日の息
desperate times, tomorrow's breath.
勇気をください 愛を知る前に
Please give me courage before I know love;
そこにいて欲しい 目を閉じる前に ねぇ
I want you to be there before I close my eyes, hey.
運命と時間 相容れない
Fate and time cannot reconcile,
絶体絶命 明日の息
desperate times, tomorrow's breath.
遠い空の星
The stars in the distant sky
平行したまま
remain in parallel,
同じ夜を願いながら
while wishing upon the same night,
見上げてた
I looked up.
全てをつなぐ線は音を立てて崩れて
The lines connecting everything collapse with a sound,
深く交ざり合うほどに夜明けを望んでいる
and as they blend deeply, I long for the dawn.
道なき道を 進んでいた
I kept advancing down a trackless path,
声なき声を 頼りにして
relying on a voiceless voice,
名もなき歌を響かせた
and made a nameless song resonate.
本当の祈りに今手を伸ばしてる
Now I'm reaching out toward a true prayer.
愚かしく美しい人生が息苦しくても
Even if a foolish and beautiful life is suffocating,
目標は高ければ高いほど乗り越える意味があるから
the higher the goal, the more meaning there is in overcoming it.
百万分の一でも夢が叶うなら
If even a one-in-a-million dream can come true,
僕は何度でも何度でも戦い続けて行くから
I will keep fighting over and over again.
あなたがいなきゃ始まらないよ
It cannot begin without you.
勝負をつけなきゃ終われないよ
It cannot end without settling the score.
僕と君の物語には誰も何も言えやしないよ
In the story of you and me, no one can say a thing.
ありきたりな世界をかたやぶりの世界へと変えられる一人じゃないから
Because I'm not alone in turning an ordinary world into an unconventional one.
真っ直ぐな道を 進む時さえ
Even when walking down a straight road,
不安だけは消えずに付きまとっていた
anxiety alone lingered without disappearing.
いつの間にか外から心を固く閉ざし
Before I knew it, I closed my heart tightly from the outside,
自分さえも忘れて誓いを破っていた
forgetting even myself and breaking my vows.
渇いた笑いを浮かべて
With a thirsty smile,
滲んだ涙を飲み干した
I drank down my blurred tears.
歪んだ想いを伝えたい
I want to convey my distorted feelings,
このまま失いそうだから
because I feel like I'm going to lose them just like this.
狂おしく美しい絶望に包み込まれても
Even if I'm wrapped in a maddening, beautiful despair,
先が暗ければ暗いほど辛く迷う日もあるけど
the darker the future ahead, the more painful days of doubt there may be,
百億年前からも光はあるから僕は最後まで
but light has existed since ten billion years ago, so until the very end, I...
僕は最後まで望みを捨てずにいなんだ
Even until the very end, I refused to give up my hope.
真実は弱く儚くて
Truth is weak and fleeting,
偽りは強く猛るもの
While falsehoods are strong and fierce.
君と僕の結末なんて白か黒じゃ決められないよ
You and I can't decide our ending as simply black or white.
ありふれてる奇跡やまちがえてる運命でも
Even ordinary miracles, or mistaken destinies,
変わりない 一つじゃないから
Are unchanging, because there's not just one.
一人で交わして
Exchanging alone,
二人で合わせたら
Combining together,
あの日の約束を 果たして…
Fulfilling the promise of that day...
愚かしく麗しい人生が息苦しくても
Even if this foolishly beautiful life is stifling,
目標は高ければ高いほど 乗り越える意味があるから
The higher the goal, the more meaning there is in overcoming it.
1,000,000/1でも 夢が叶うなら
Even if it's a one in a million chance, if the dream comes true,
僕は何度でも何度でも 戦い続けていくから
I will keep fighting over and over again.
主役がいなきゃ始まらないよ 勝負をつけなきゃ終われないよ
It can't begin without the main character, and it can't end without settling the score.
君の物語には誰も何も言えやしないよ
In your story, no one can say a thing.
ありふれた世界をかたやぶりな世界へと変える
Turning an ordinary world into an unconventional one,
一人じゃないから
Because we're not alone.
決められたバイナリに従います 社交界の作法に溶け込みます
I obey the assigned binary; I blend into the etiquette of high society.
それで価値の器が満たされると信じてた。
Believing that would fill the vessel of my value.
舞踏会に溢れた息遣い その裏にありあまる思惑が重なり合って気付いたんだ
The breaths overflowing in the ball, the excessive ulterior motives behind them overlapping, making me realize—
器の下は底抜けの状態だったんだ。
The bottom of the vessel was completely missing.
器を満たす意味は潰え 積み重ねたもの元通りに
The meaning to fill the vessel is shattered, returning piled-up things to how they were.
無に帰す惨めな姿と 現状を抱える今日日に
In these modern days holding onto a miserable appearance that returns to nothing.
してやったという優越感を かけらも奴らに与えないように
So as not to give those guys even a scrap of superiority of having done it,
流れ出した価値を仲間と取り返そう 自ら器を作っていこう
Let's take back the flowing value with our friends and forge our own vessels.
定石通りに動いてちゃ こんな人生つまんないな
Moving strictly by the book makes such a life so boring.
それならいっそギアなんか壊して 自分が望んだ結末をはめ込んでやれ
If so, smash the gears altogether and force in the ending you wished for!
ティーカップ裏に仕込んだ情報で 主役を演じていけ
Play the leading role with information tucked behind the teacup.
信じたものを守り抜くことができるこの世界は 私だけの人生だ！
This world where you can protect what you believe in is my life alone!
台本通りにかけられた言葉と 道行く人々の思想と顔 そのすべてが作り物であるとするならば、
If the words cast strictly by the script, the thoughts and faces of passersby, and all of that are fabricated creations,
誰よりも強いこの意志で すべて塗り替えてしまうような
With this will stronger than anyone else's, like painting over everything,
誰をもが想像しなかった新たな未来へ！
Toward a new future that no one could have ever imagined!
定石通りに動いてちゃ こんな人生つまんないな
Moving strictly by the book makes such a life so boring.
それならいっそギアなんか壊して 自分が望んだ結末をはめ込んでやれ
If so, smash the gears altogether and force in the ending you wished for!
ティーカップ裏に仕込んだ情報で 主役を演じていけ
Play the leading role with information tucked behind the teacup.
信じたものを守り抜くことができるこの世界は 私だけの人生だ！
This world where you can protect what you believe in is my life alone!
わたしだけの人生だ
A life that's uniquely mine!
決められたバイナリに抗います 社交界の作法に阿ねません
Resisting the set binary, not pandering to society's ways,
それで満たされる価値があることに気付いたんだ
I realized there's value in being fulfilled by that.
舞踏会に溢れた息遣い その裏をありあまる思惑を
Breaths filling the ballroom, and the overflowing motives behind them—
跳ね除け切って残ったのは 人生の真の面白さだ
brushing them all aside, what remains is the true fun of life!
見慣れた景色に潜むアイデア いつだって君は監視されている
Ideas lurking in familiar scenery, you're always being watched.
クルクル野原結び合わせて まわる青色のカレイドスコープ
Twirling wild flowers together, a spinning blue kaleidoscope.
無意識バイアス 誰も知らない存在理由 繰り返し思い描くスピログラフ
Unconscious bias, a reason for being nobody knows, drawing spirals over and over.
破壊と創造の幾何学模様 打ち切り前の先でまた会えるよ
Geometric patterns of destruction and creation, we'll meet again beyond the cancellation.
パラレルワールド旅して 散らばる願いに気付いて 世界をリメイク
Traveling through parallel worlds, noticing scattered wishes, remaking the world.
隙間もない狭苦しいお庭 粉々にして取り替えてよ
Replace this cramped garden with no room to spare, smashing it to bits!
無から生まれ無に帰れ！全部 何度でもディストピアを越えて
Born from nothing, return to nothing! Everything, overcoming the dystopia time and again.
またお別れね 次の界で待ってるから 戻れない
It's farewell again, I'll be waiting in the next world, you can't go back.
変幻のマンダラ 思い出も崩れてしまえば意味がない
Changing mandala, if memories crumble away it has no meaning.
君も忘れるだけ 何度も手を振る私は 懲りもせず光当ててるんだ
You'll just forget too. Waving my hand over and over, shining a light without learning my lesson.
デザイン変えたい 壊さなきゃ見られない
I want to change the design, can't see it unless I break it.
離脱！観賞用のフラワーアレンジメント
Withdrawal! Flower arrangement for viewing.
ミラーシステムは君を箱庭に閉じ込めた キラキラの鏡ぶち壊して新世界へ！
The mirror system trapped you in a miniature garden, smash the sparkling mirror and head to the new world!
降り上げろ！ バイバイララバイ バイバイシャバイ未来 毎回来れない
Swing it down! Bye-bye lullaby, bye-bye mundane future, can't come every time.
バイバイシャバイWi-Fiパラダイス バイバイララバイ バイバイシャバイ未来 出会いたい
Bye-bye mundane Wi-Fi paradise, bye-bye lullaby, bye-bye mundane future, I want to meet you.
殺さなきゃ見れない 見たことない景色に踏み込むイデア
Ideas stepping into unseen scenery, can't see unless you kill.
いつだって君は監視されている クルクル野原結び合わせて まわる青色のカレイドスコープ
You're always being watched, twirling wild flowers together, a spinning blue kaleidoscope.
無意識バイアス 誰も知らない存在理由 繰り返し思い描くスピログラフ
Unconscious bias, a reason for being nobody knows, drawing spirals over and over.
破壊と創造の幾何学模様 打ち切り前の先でまた会えるよ パラレルワールド旅して
Geometric patterns of destruction and creation, we'll meet again beyond the cancellation, traveling through parallel worlds.
散らばる願いに気付いて 世界をリメイク 隙間もない狭苦しいお庭
Noticing scattered wishes, remaking the world, this cramped garden with no room to spare.
粉々にして取り替えてよ 無から生まれ無に帰れ！全部
Replace it to bits, born from nothing, return to nothing! Everything.
何度でもディストピアを越えて 君がない 君も忘れるだけ 何度も手を振る
Overcoming the dystopia time and again, without you, you'll just forget too, waving my hand over and over.
私たちは懲りもせず光当ててるんだ デザイン変えたい 壊さなきゃ見られない
Shining a light without learning our lesson, I want to change the design, can't see it unless I break it.
離脱！観賞用のフラワーアレンジメント
Withdrawal! Flower arrangement for viewing.
バイバイララバイ バイバイシャバイ未来 毎回来れない
Bye-bye lullaby, bye-bye mundane future, can't come every time.
バイバイシャバイWi-Fiパラダイス バイバイララバイ バイバイシャバイ未来 出たい
Bye-bye mundane Wi-Fi paradise, bye-bye lullaby, bye-bye mundane future, I want to get out.
変えたい 殺さなきゃ見れない 見たことない景色に踏み込むイデア
I want to change it, can't see unless you kill, ideas stepping into unseen scenery.
いつだって君は監視されている クルクル野原結び合わせて
You're always being watched, twirling wild flowers together,
まわる青色のカレイドスコープ 無意識バイアス 誰も知らない存在理由
a spinning blue kaleidoscope. Unconscious bias, a reason for being nobody knows.
ミラーシステムは君を箱庭に閉じ込めた 揺らぎ揺らジェンダー
The mirror system trapped you in a miniature garden, swaying and shaking gender.
見慣れた景色に潜むアイデア
Ideas hide in the familiar scenery,
いつだって君は監視されてる
you're always under observation.
クルクル野花結び合わせて
Twirling wild flowers together,
まわる青色のカレイドスコープ
the spinning blue kaleidoscope.
無意識バイアス
Unconscious bias,
誰も知らない存在理由
a reason for being no one knows.
繰り返し　思い描くスパイログラフ
Repeating, a spirograph drawn in mind,
破壊と創造の幾何学模様
geometric patterns of destruction and creation.
打ち切りの先でまた会えるよ
We'll meet again beyond the cutoff,
パラレルワールド旅して
journeying through parallel worlds,
散らばる願いに気付いて
noticing the scattered wishes,
世界をリメイク！
and remaking the world!
隙間もない狭苦しいお庭を粉々にして取り替えてよ
Smash and replace the cramped garden with no gaps!
無から生まれ無に帰れ！全部
Born from nothing, return to nothing! All of it,
何度でもディストピアを越えて
overcoming dystopia time and time again.
またお別れね
It's goodbye once again,
次の世界で待ってるから
I'll be waiting for you in the next world.
戻れない　変幻のマンダラ
There's no turning back, a shifting mandala,
想い出も崩れてしまえ
let even memories crumble away.
意味がない　君も忘れるだけ
It's meaningless, you'll just forget,
何度でも手を振る私は　懲りれず光当ててんだ
waving my hand repeatedly, shining light without learning.
バイバイ　ララバイ
Bye-bye, lullaby,
バイバイ　シャバイ　ミライ
bye-bye, shabby future,
マイカイ　ブレン　アイ　バイバイ　シャバイ　パラダイス
every time, brand-new love, bye-bye, shabby paradise.
ねぇねぇ、二人とも
Hey, hey, you two.
タルマさんが転んだしながら
While playing "Daruma-san ga koronda",
この3年間でやったことない動きしよう。
let's do movements we've never done in these 3 years.
いいよ！
Sure!
最初は…
First...
じゃんけんぽい！
Rock, paper, scissors!
あいこでしょ！
Aiko de sho!
行くよ、みんな！
Here we go, everyone!
タルマさんが転んだ！
Daruma-san ga koronda!
ラミィさんこっち来て！お前運転して！
Lamy-san, come over here! You drive!
一緒にやって、お尻振るだけ。せーの、タルマさんが転んだ！
Do it with me, just shaking hips. Ready, set, Daruma-san ga koronda!
近い！
So close!
あれ、ししろん、本日の主役？駆けつけてきてくれたの？
Wait, Shishiron, today's protagonist? You rushed over?
そうだよ！ししろんも行くよ！行くよ！
That's right! Shishiron is going too! Let's go!
止まれ！止！
Stop! Stop!
だめじゃん！
No good!
ラミィ、じゃんけん、じゃんけんぽい！
Lamy, rock-paper-scissors, rock, paper, scissors!
ぽい！
Poi!
いつまでやるの？
How long are we doing this?
あいこでしょ！
Aiko de sho!
いつまでやるの？
How long are we doing this?
あいこでしょ！
Aiko de sho!
え、負けた！
Eh, I lost!
タルマ…い！
Daruma... i!
ちょっと待って！
Wait a minute!
あー！
Ah!
今日何？後ろ見えないじゃん、これ！
What is this today? We can't see behind us at all!
これがライブです！
This is a live!
見えねえわ！
We can't see!
ということで私、ししろんのちょっと遅れた、あの3周年記念の…
So, a little late for my 3rd anniversary, Shishiron's...
おめでとう！
Congratulations!
え、さっきさ、なんか3年経って見たことない動きって言ってたじゃん。
Wait, earlier you said movements we've never seen in 3 years, right?
ねねちゃんの動き、たぶん全部見たことあるよ。
Nene-chan's movements, I've probably seen all of them.
じゃんけん、
Rock, paper,
rock, paper,
え、動きがいい、これ、これ。
Eh, this movement is good, this one.
ねねちゃんの動きって、のろまの…
Nene-chan's movements are like a slowpoke...
高速バージョン？
High-speed version?
さっきやってたやつ。
The one we did earlier.
あんまり見ないかな。
Don't see that very often.
あんまり見ないやつだよあれ。
That's a rare one.
なんかストップウォッチだらけで、満腹系めっちゃ！ししろんみたいになってる！
Full of stopwatches, so full! Like Shishiron!
ちょっとお前らのを見ておきたい。
I want to see you guys'.
え、何よ？
Eh, what?
3年で初めて始める動き？
A movement starting for the first time in 3 years?
3年で初めて始める動き、こういう感じ？
A movement for the first time in 3 years, like this?
うーん…ちょっと待って、もっと縦に…
Um... wait, more vertically...
上下に、上下に揺れたほうがいいかもな。確かに！ふうふうって進むの？
Up and down, swaying up and down might be better. True! Moving with a puff-puff?
体力モーション、体力モーションなんだよねこれ。
Stamina motion, it's stamina motion.
え、だってさ、ししろんをそこから何…
Eh, because Shishiron, from there, what...
え、なんかあるかな？
Eh, is there anything?
3年間やったことない…なんで？なんでかわいそうだよ、主役が。
Haven't done in 3 years... Why? Why is it pitiful, the protagonist?
え、そのままずっと上下に飛び跳ねたらカエルみたいで可愛いと思う、これ。
Eh, if you just keep jumping up and down like a frog, it's cute, this one.
これ、変なんだよ！でもないわ、これないわ！
This is weird! But no, this is not it!
ダメダメダメダメ！もっと二人でやったほうがいいな！み、見とれ！見とれ！
No no no no! Better to do it together! Watch, watch!
いや、見たことあるんだよ、な、これ。絶対ねねちゃんの全部見たことあるんだよな！
No, I've seen this before. I've definitely seen all of Nene-chan's!
激しい！激しい！
Intense! Intense!
4人で歌って踊るんでしょ？
We're going to sing and dance with 4 people, right?
あ、そうそう。じゃあししろん、え、なんだろう今日、何歌う？
Oh, right. So Shishiron, um, I wonder what we're singing today?
え、何歌うの？今から決めるの？
Eh, what are we singing? Deciding from now?
でも決まってるんで、え？何何？
But it's decided, eh? What, what?
なんか、私たちいつもさ、ブルクラ歌う人みたいになってるじゃん。
Like, we always look like people who sing Blue Clapper.
違う、ブルクラ歌いすぎなんです！
No, we sing Blue Clapper too much!
だから今日は、ま、今日は3周年記念っていうことは、みんなも要は3周年経ったわけだから、
So today, well, today being the 3rd anniversary means everyone has passed 3 years,
やっぱちゃんとカッコいい歌を歌いたいなっていうのがあるじゃん、やっぱりカッコいいバージョンのブルクラ？
so naturally we want to sing a cool song, right? Like a cool version of Blue Clapper?
違うよ！ヘヴィメタルでやったでしょ！
No! We did it in heavy metal!
ヘヴィメタルでやったでしょ！なんなら、今日も、ちょっとカッコいいやつをみんなで歌いたいなと思うんで、
We did it in heavy metal! If anything, today I want us all to sing something cool,
よろしくお願いします！
so please look forward to it!
よろしくお願いしまーす！
Looking forward to it!
じゃあ、気を取り直して、じゃあポジションついて、みんな！
Well then, pulling ourselves together, everyone take your positions!
で、その前にですね、ちょっと私の新しい、新しい新曲がね、出るので…
And before that, my new, brand new song is coming out...
え！オリジナル曲の！
Eh! An original song!
そちらを何だった？歌わせてくだざい！
Please let us sing that!
全然噛んだことないMC。そう言う新しいの！
An MC that never stumbled. Saying something new!
あの、まあぶっちゃけた話し言うと、まあ、喋りに来てくれるよなと思って、
Um, to be honest, I thought you'd come talk to me,
ししろん、それを聞いてほしいよ。
Shishiron, I want you to listen to that.
気軽に呼んだし、
I called you casually,
じゃあししろんボタンの入手法は後ろで見に行こうか。聞いていてください。
Then let's watch Shishiro Botan's acquisition method from behind. Please listen.
じゃあ、このあとみんな乱入してきて、結局は歌うんだ！
Then, everyone crashes in after this, and in the end, we sing!
待って待って、まだ喋れねえ！
Wait, wait, we can't talk yet!
ブルーカップアゲインでございますけれども！
It's Blue Cup Again!
ええ、獅白さんの曲どんな曲かなって、みんな！
Everyone, I wonder what kind of song Shishiro-san's will be!
どんな曲が予想する？コメントお願いします！
What kind of song do you expect? Please leave a comment!
獅白ボタンの曲どんな曲かなって、みんな！
I wonder what kind of song Shishiro Botan's will be, everyone!
あー楽しみだね、獅白ボタンの曲！
Ah, I'm so looking forward to Shishiro Botan's song!
はい、はい、はい！おい！おい！おい！おい！
Hey, hey, hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
あ、じゃあこの後も頑張ってください！
Ah, well then, please do your best afterwards!
獅白ボタンの曲楽しみだね！うわー！
I'm looking forward to Shishiro Botan's song! Wow!
Connect:Addict
答え探し彷徨ってる
Wandering in search of the answer...
(何処にもない)
(Nowhere to be found)
教えてよ 持て余した僕の正しい使い方
Tell me how to make good use of my surplus self.
ふいに1秒導かれて
Guided suddenly by a single second...
(鐘が響く)
(A bell rings)
ヒビ割れた液晶の中飛び込んだ仮想現実
Virtual reality I jumped into, inside a cracked liquid crystal screen.
目が眩むような突然の閃光
A sudden flash of light that dazzles the eyes.
羽化する鼓動 生まれ変わるんだ
A heartbeat taking flight, being reborn.
純白のbutterfly 自由にmidnight
A pure white butterfly, free in the midnight.
何もかもが全て揃う時代に (巡り合う)
In an era where everything falls into place (crossing paths)...
キミは唯一僕を求めた
You alone desired me.
コネクトされる僕等の日々
Our days of being connected.
昨日よりも上手く息が出来る気がする 怖くない
I feel like I can breathe better than yesterday. I'm not afraid.
“オウトウセョ、そちらはどう？”
"Come in, how is it over there?"
(雨のちはれ)
(Fair weather after the rain)
感情がコンバートして文字となり流れていく
Emotions convert into text, flowing away.
キミの世界届けるハロー (聞こえますか？)
Hello, reaching your world (Can you hear me?)
遠い街 同じ唄で眠りつく奇跡的現実
A miraculous reality of falling asleep to the same song in a distant town.
モノクロだった
The monochrome,
見慣れた画面が
familiar screen...
いつの間にか万華鏡みたいだ
Has somehow become like a kaleidoscope.
夢うつつaddiction 魅惑なmission
A daydream addiction, an alluring mission.
ガランドウな身体を今、満たそう (煌めいて)
Let's fill this hollow body now (shining bright).
誰年もが虜になる
Anyone and everyone becomes captivated.
秒薬の鱗粉 触れた瞬間
The moment we touched the mysterious dust of scales.
退屈も刺激帯びてゆくことをキミに教えるよ
I'll teach you that even boredom starts to carry a thrill.
誰かが放つノイズで羽が破れても キミの元へと
Even if someone's noise tears your wings apart, heading to your side...
純白のbutterfly 自由にmidnight
A pure white butterfly, free in the midnight.
何もかもが全て揃う時代に (巡り合う)
In an era where everything falls into place (crossing paths)...
キミは唯一僕を求めた
You alone desired me.
コネクトされる僕等の日々
Our days of being connected.
昨日よりもキミを近くに感じられる
I can feel you closer than yesterday.
抱きしめて
Hold me tight.
始まる歌 始まる鼓動
The song begins, the heartbeat begins,
響き渡れ 希望の音
the sound of hope echoing through.
「生きる事を諦めない」と
"Don't give up on living,"
示せ
it shows.
熱き夢の幕開けを爆ぜろ
Burst open the curtain of passionate dreams!
この奇跡に嘘はない
There are no lies in this miracle!
その手は何を掴む為にある?
What are those hands for, to grasp?
たぶん待ただけじゃ叶わない
Just waiting won't make it come true.
その手は何を守る為にある?
What are those hands for, to protect?
伝う熱は明後を輝かす種火に
The passing heat makes tomorrow shine!
さあ新時代へ銃爪を引こう
Now, let's pull the trigger into a new era,
伝説の未来へとカウントダウン
countdown to a legendary future!
その手は何を掴む為にある?
What are those hands for, to grasp?
たぶん待ただけじゃ叶わない
Just waiting won't make it come true.
その手は何を守る為にある?
What are those hands for, to protect?
伝う熱は
The passing heat...
明日を輝かす種火に
...makes tomorrow shine!
さあ新時代へ銃爪を引こう
Now, pull the trigger into a new era,
伝説の未来へとカウントダウン
countdown to a legendary future!
羽撃きは一人じゃない
Flapping wings are not alone.
過去を超えた先に 創るべき歴史が
Beyond the past, the history we ought to create...
咲き燃えてる
...is blazing and burning!
絆、心、一つに束ね
Unite our bonds and hearts as one,
響き渡れ希望の音
let the sound of hope echo through!
「信ずる事を諦めない」と
"Don't give up believing,"
歌え可能性にゼロはない
sing it, there's no zero in possibilities!
飛べよ この奇跡に光あれ
Fly into this miracle, let there be light!
切り裂け まだ見ぬ日に行く為に
Slash through to go to unseen days,
不可能なんて何一つない
there is nothing impossible!
こんなに心強い事はない
There is nothing more reassuring!
絶対 絶対 絶対 信じ合いぶっちぎる
Definitely, definitely believing in each other...
例え闇に吸い込まれそうになって
Even if darkness threatens to swallow us,
涙さえも血に濡れて苦しくても
even if tears are soaked in blood and painful,
帰る場所が待っている
the place to return is waiting!
集え 守れ 契れ
Gather, protect, pledge,
勇気の結晶が奇跡なんだ
the crystallization of courage is a miracle!
願い、祈り、すべてを背負い
Carrying all wishes and prayers,
本気を越えた本気の歌
a serious song that surpasses seriousness!
痛みなんて何も怖くない
Pain is nothing to be afraid of,
滾れ沸騰させよ このカラダ
surge and boil, this body!
さあ闇夜に稲妻を
Now, unleash lightning in the dark night!
出会い笑い合い そして泣きじゃくり
Meet, smile together, and then cry bitterly,
命の炎も 一緒に燃やして
burn the flame of life together!
五感の全部が叫ぶ
all five senses scream,
眩しく煌めいた友の証
a dazzling and brilliant proof of friendship!
絆、心、一つに束ね
Unite our bonds and hearts as one,
響き渡れ希望の音
let the sound of hope echo through!
「信ずる事を諦めない」と
"Don't give up believing,"
歌え可能性にゼロはない
sing it, there's no zero in possibilities!
飛べよ この奇跡に光あれ
Fly into this miracle, let there be light!